Guide to the C.K. Woodbridge papers, 1917-1997 and undated RL.11737
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
C.K. Woodbridge papers
1917-1997 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Woodbridge, C. K. (Charles Kingsley), b. 1881.
RL.11737
6.0 Linear Feet
Advertising and business executive. President of Dictaphone Corporation (1922-1927, 1948-1960), based in New York. President of Associated Advertising Clubs of the World and International Advertising Association (precursor to American Advertising Federation). C.K. Woodbridge papers include correspondence, text and notes for speeches and writings, clippings, scrapbooks, black-and-white photographs, audio belt recordings and other printed materials. Topics addressed include the management, training and compensation of sales personnel; women in the advertising business; corporate management and public relations; internationalization of advertising and marketing and the role of professional organizations; and product development (importation of margarine from the Netherlands to the U.S. and Canada; popularization of dictating equipment in office spaces). Companies and organizations represented include Advertising Club of New York, American Machine and Metals (parent company of Trout Mining), Anton Jurgens Margarine Works (precursor of Unilever), Associated Advertising Clubs of the World, Dictaphone, Incorporated Sales Managers' Association (UK), International Advertising Association (later renamed Advertising Federation of America merged to become the present American Advertising Federation), Kelvinator, League of Advertising Women, Philadelphia Club of Advertising Women, Remington Rand, and Spencer Kellogg & Sons. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General Files; Dictaphone Corporation; Speeches; Writings; Scrapbook collection
Biographical / Historical
Advertising and business executive, President of Dictaphone Corporation (1922-1927, 1948-1960), based in New York. President of Associated Advertising Clubs of the World and International Advertising Association (precursor to American Advertising Federation).
Born 1881 New Hampshire; BS Dartmouth College 1904; Early career (Adriance Plat; Preston & Keith; Loose-Wiles Biscuit Co.); Kellogg Products 1917-1918; President and Chair, Dictaphone Corporation 1922-1927; Executive Vice President, Electric Refrigeration Corporation (Kelvinator) 1927-1929; President, American Machine and Metals 1930; Vice-President, Remington Rand Business Services 1931; Chairman, Dictaphone 1948-1960; died 1960, London.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The C.K. Woodbridge papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2006 and 2015.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
International Advertising Association. International Advertising Exposition exhibitor handouts
J. Walter Thompson Company. 35mm microfilm proofs
J. Walter Thompson Company. Account files
J. Walter Thompson Company. Competitive advertisements
J. Walter Thompson Company. Norman Strouse papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Shirley F. Woodell papers
James O'Shaughnessy papers
John W. Crawford papers
Strobridge Lithographing Company advertisements
Collection Overview
C.K. Woodbridge papers include correspondence, text and notes for speeches and writings, clippings, scrapbooks, black-and-white photographs, audio belt recordings and other printed materials. Topics addressed include the management, training and compensation of sales personnel; women in the advertising business; corporate management and public relations; internationalization of advertising and marketing and the role of professional organizations; and product development (importation of margarine from the Netherlands to the U.S. and Canada; popularization of dictating equipment in office spaces). Companies and organizations represented include Advertising Club of New York, American Machine and Metals (parent company of Trout Mining), Anton Jurgens Margarine Works (precursor of Unilever), Associated Advertising Clubs of the World, Dictaphone, Incorporated Sales Managers' Association (UK), International Advertising Association (later renamed Advertising Federation of America merged to become the present American Advertising Federation), Kelvinator, League of Advertising Women, Philadelphia Club of Advertising Women, Remington Rand, and Spencer Kellogg & Sons. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising -- United States -- History; Advertising executives -- United States; Women in the advertising industry; Sales executives -- United States; Sales personnel -- United States; Sales management -- United States; Selling -- United States; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Associated Advertising Clubs of America; American Advertising Federation; Advertising Federation of America; International Advertising Association; Unilever (Firm) -- History; Dictaphone Corp.
- General Files, 1917-1960, 1997; 1
  - Achievement Club, 1949-1959 (Box 1)
  - Advertising Club of New York, 1927 (Box 1)
  - Advertising Club of New York--Advertising Club News, 1925-1929 (Box 3)
  - American Machine and Metals (binder), 1930; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Articles on National Secretaries' Day, 1997 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    45th anniversary of the holiday; article notes Woodbridge was one of the original advocates for a day of recognition for secretarial staff
  - Associated Advertising Clubs of the World, 1923-1925 (Box 1)
  - Association of National Advertisers meeting program, 1952 (Box 1)
  - British Advertising Convention Told in Pictures, 1925 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1925-1950; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1925, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Clippings--The Fourth Estate, 1926 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1931-1957 (Box 1)
  - International Advertising Conference, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Kellogg Products--Anton Jurgens Margarine Works correspondence and reports, 1917-1918 (Box 1)
  - Obituaries, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 1927-1952 and undated (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 1925-1937 (Box 3)
  - Photographs, 1937, 1951 (Oversize-folder 1)
    Advertising Federation of America annual banquet room shot, 1937; dinner in honor of Ellsworth Bunker given by the sugar industry, room shot, 1951
  - University of Chattanooga convocation, 1955-1956; 2 folders (Box 1)
- Dictaphone Corporation, 1924-1958; 2
  - Annual Reports, 1955-1956 (Box 1)
  - Feature in Magazine of Management, 1949 (Box 1)
  - How the Dictaphone Time-Master Speeds Justice I Puerto Rico, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Memos and miscellaneous, 1924-1958 (Box 1)
  - Print ad featuring Woodbridge, approximately 1928 (Box 3)
  - Publications--Executives Say, 1927 (Box 1)
  - Publications--It's Said and Done, 1950-1957 (Box 1)
  - Publications--Secretaries Say, 1927 (Box 1)
  - Publications--The Dictaphone Record, 1956 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Publications--The Mouthpiece, 1926-1958 (Box 1)
  - Speeches and memos, 1919, 1949 and undated (Box 2)
- Speeches, 1918-1954; 3
  - Advertising's Place in the Building or Rebuilding of a Business, approximately 1954 (Box 2)
  - American Society of Sales Executives, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Connecticut Personnel Association, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Intensive Selling vs. Hitting the High Spots, 1918 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1948-1949 (Box 2)
  - Moving an Inventory, 1920 (Box 2)
  - Newcomen Society, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Platz Club, 1949 (Box 2)
- Writings, 1924-1952; 4
  - Conventions Reveal to Public Importance of Advertising, 1925 (Box 2)
    Includes: Bernice Blackwood, Activities of Women in Organized Advertising
  - Cooperative Research in Sales Management (John Stevenson and C.K. Woodbridge), 1924 (Box 2)
  - Creating and Maintaining Morale among Sales Forces, 1928 (Box 2)
  - Dictaphone Electronic Genius of Voice and Typed Word, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Just as the Curtain Fell (Adcrafter), 1928 (Box 3)
  - Salesmanship and Advertising, 1926 (Box 2)
  - The Church and the Community, 1942 (Box 2)
  - What Can Be Done Internationally for Advertising, 1932 (Box 2)
- Dictaphone belts from CKW to Josephine Woodbridge and family, 1955 and undated; 5
  - CKW from Switzerland June, 1955 (Box 4)
  - CKW on board June, 1955 (Box 4)
  - CKW received 6/13/55, 1955 (Box 4)
  - From CKW June 7, 1955 (Box 4)
  - From CKW June 14, 1955 (Box 4)
  - From CKW June 19, 1955 (Box 4)
  - From London, 1955 (Box 4)
  - Unlabeled, undated (Box 4)
  - Dictaphone mailer, undated (Box 4)
- Scrapbook Collection, 1922-1931; 6
  - Scrapbook 1, 1922-1925 (Box 5)
    Includes: clippings about Woodbridge; caricatures; Advertising Club of New York; Dictaphone Corporation; Associated Advertising Clubs of the World; death of Warren G. Harding; Dartmouth Alumni Association; Incorporated Sales Managers Association of the UK
  - Scrapbook 2, 1925-1926 (Box 6)
    Includes: clippings about Woodbridge; Associated Advertising Clubs of the World; news about various ad clubs. Materials in English, French, Dutch.
  - Scrapbook 3, 1926-1927 (Box 7)
    Includes: articles by and about Woodbridge; international advertising clubs and meetings; Electric Refrigeration Corporation (Kelvinator); women's advertising clubs including League of Advertising Women. Materials in English, French, German.
  - Scrapbook 4, 1928-1931 (Box 8)
    Includes: articles by and about Woodbridge; International Advertising Association; advertising clubs in Michigan; Continental Advertising Association (material in English, French, German); Kelvinator; salesman compensation; Remington Rand Business Services